To start, me and my mother-in-law have never gotten along.
She hates my guts and can be oversensitive oftentimes.
I tried not to give her the wrong impression about me, but we just don't like each other.
Sunday, I was feeling sick. I'm a new mom, by the way,
and couldn't eat what she cooked for dinner, and she seemed to take it personal.
She sent me a private message of what seemed to be her final straw with my behavior,
and it stated the following, copy, paste.
Oh yes, I know, and feel your passive-aggressive vibe.
You keep pretending to be sick so you won't have to eat what I cook.
What? You think my cooking is disgusting?
You think I'm unhygienic?
When was the last time you actually looked at yourself in the mirror?
Apologies, I forgot you're a new mom and can't be bothered to even get your hair brushed.
You finally trapped our son and now want to use the baby as a pawn.
Oh, like the fact you're my grandchild's mother.
I don't think I'll ever come to terms with it because you bore him.
But I'll pretend.
Pretend I don't know my son's been having chats with his ex every chance he gets.
Be mean to his mommy.
Me? And you'll see how far that gets you.
Oh, and when I watch your shit beast dog,
it stays chained to a garage day and night until a half hour before you arrive.
It stinks at my house, you know, same with your hair and clothes.
My mind was blown and my gut reaction was to immediately go to my husband
and show him what his mom sent and he didn't take it well.
He tried calling her but she didn't respond.
It was 11 p.m. and he decided to drive to his parents' house
and pick a fight with her about the text.
According to my sister-in-law, number one, who witnessed it,
he yelled at his mother and berated her and call her her names
then disowned her, which shocked everyone in the house.
My mother-in-law is diabetic.
She fainted on the spot and my husband didn't stop.
He just walked out of there while his family were yelling at him.
I got several calls and texts from them claiming I just caused irreparable damage
in my husband's relationship with his mother,
jeopardized her health because she was taken to the hospital,
and worse of all, making my husband disown her over what?
A dinner that I could have gotten a few bites of?
A simple misunderstanding?
They accused me of causing this shit show
and turning my husband on his own mother and disowning her like that.
Sister-in-law number three berated me for sharing the text with my husband saying,
I should have confronted my mother-in-law alone instead of escalating the situation.
She said I'm responsible for whatever happens next
and have to fix the problem I created.
I feel awful overall and so guilty since she's at the hospital
and the family are feeling tense.
My husband is avoiding me.